Contact

20 Heatherdale Drive Brampton, Ontario +15144662753 (Mobile) segebantin2050@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sotolaolusegun-ba6b26273 (LinkedIn) www.linkedin.com/in/sotolaolusegun-ba6b26273 (Personal)

Top Skills

prometheus, Grafana, sonarqube, GIThub

maven, terraform, sonaqurbe Git, jenkins, Docker

Sotola Olusegun

DevOps Engineer || SRE| | PROMETHEUS| | GRAFANA | |Teraform | | Kubernetes || Jenkins || Docker|Terraform || Ansible| Cloud Computing | Sonarqube || GitHub || Git || EC2 || S3 | IAM || VPC || Auto Scaling ||

Brampton, Ontario, Canada

Summary

A skilled professional Devops Engineer with added skills as an SRE integrating Machine Language to creactive accurate predictions of data analysis and optimizing mission critical deployments in AWS, designing and implementing CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins, infrasructure provisioning, fault-tolerant and scalable infrastructures on AWS utilizing terraform or Cloud Formation and cloud security, Strong experienced with open source tools like sonaqube (Jenkins, GitHub, Maven, SonarQube, Ansible, Tomcat, Terraform), Microservices (Kubernetes, Docker, Prometheus, Graphana, EFK) and AWS services (VPC,SG, EC2, S3,, Cloudwatch, CloudTrail, AWS Config,

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES:

Debugging Tracking:, static and Dynamic Testing

CI: Jenkins, Code Build.

Cloud Technologies: Amazon Web Services.

Configuration Management: Ansible.

Container Orchestration: EKS, ECS, AWS-Fargate.

Containerization: Docker. Kubernetes Deployment: Jenkins, Code Deploy.

Infrastructure as A Service (code): Terraform, Jenkins File, Ansible.

Languages: Shell scripting, Yaml.

Operating Systems: Windows, RHEL, CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu.

Project Management / Ticketing: artifacts sharing.

Experience

Landmark Technologies SNR DevOps Engineer March 2018 - Present (5 years 5 months) Canada

- Usage of GITS, GITHUB and building of Artifacts and testing of using Sonarqube, maintain automated CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, Docker, and AWS CodePipeline for faster and more reliable software delivery.
- Manage cloud infrastructure on AWS using Terraform and Ansible.
 development sprints.
- Develop and maintain automation scripts using bash scripts, Ansible, and Terraform.
- . Set up Git repositories and SSH Keys in GitHub for Agile teams
- Application Delivery. Jenkins, Bitbucket, AWS CodePipeline, AWS Code Commit, Code build and Code deploy.
- Create Ansible playbooks for automating infrastructure deployment and configuration management.
- Use shell scripts and Splunk for log analysis and monitoring, and troubleshooting.
- Conduct Kubernetes cluster performance analysis and tuning for applications running inside pods to improve performance.
- Set up CI Pipeline that checks out the code from SCM and packages it is using a Microsoft-hosted agent/ VMSS build tool,
- Provides code analysis with SonarQube, and uploads to Artifactory.
- Setup repository on Azure Git, merging code from develop one branch to the master branch and preparing it for deployment

Dynamic System Solutions, Inc. Site Reliability Engineer SRE May 2014 - October 2017 (3 years 6 months)

Lagos State, Nigeria

- 1,Strong K8s (OpenShift or otherwise) working knowledge with experience and understanding of CICD pipeline and DevOps / Agile Methodology
- 2, Extensive Logging and Monitoring of alerts to prevent outages or downtimes to ensure 100% system Reliability.
- 3, Experience with cloud platforms like AWS, GCP, or Azure
- 4,Exposure to Cloud, SaaS, and virtualization concepts and performance management system like Puppet, Chef or Salt;
- 5, Experience with ELK infrastructures with strong knowledge of Kibana; Working knowledge of Dynatrace.
- 6, Experience designing and building reliable systems
- 7, Experience in the following IaC systems; Terraform, ARM Templates
- 8, Ability to dive deep to find the root cause of an issue, and willingness to dive into understanding and improving any layer of the stack

9, Good communication skills, strong problem solving and leadership skills, and driven by curiosity.

Techworld Solutions
Network System Engineer
April 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 7 months)
Lagos State, Nigeria

- 1,Installing, configuring and supporting network equipment including routers, proxy servers, switches, WAN accelerators, DNS and DHCP
- 2,Procuring network equipment and managing subcontractors involved with network installation
- 3, Configuring firewalls, routing and switching to maximise network efficiency and security
- 4, Maximising network performance through ongoing monitoring and troubleshooting
- 5, Arranging scheduled upgrades
- 6, Investigating faults in the network
- 6, Updating network equipment to the latest firmware releases
- 7, Reporting network status to key stakeholders

Education

York University Toronto Canada
Associate's degree, Software Development and Operations
DEVOPS · (September 2018 - July 2019)

Federal University of Technology Akure Nigeria

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering · (March 2003 - September 2007)

The Polytechnic, Ibadan, Nigeria
Higher National Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (April 1998 - May 2000)

Federal Polytechnic Ilaro, Ogun state Nigeria National Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (February 1995 - September 1997)